Aunt,
have a sip of tea and take your time.
Three years ago,
your eldest cousin
trusted the wrong people.
He couldn't refuse them
out of politeness
and was forced
to ghostwrite that essay.
Now, it's been dug up.
You know
your grandfather is strictly principled.
He definitely won't step forward
to plead for him.
Your uncle is furious,
but he has no other way either.
Xihe,
I am truly at my wits' end.
That's why I've come to beg you.
Your Highness, I urge you
to consider carefully.
There are three thousand candidates
this year.
If, as you said, we
investigate this to the very end,
I'm afraid
half of the noble families
will be wearing mourning clothes.
Your Highness,
the Censorate executed
twenty-seven people in seven days,
causing a mutiny in the border army.
Furthermore, corrupt officials
are using the fraud case
to frame the loyal and good.
I am not afraid of cutting out the sore,
but of damaging the heart
and lungs in the process.
We are willing to risk our lives
to guarantee a thorough investigation,
but please make it clear, Your Highness.
If the case reaches the Censorate
and a prince's disciple passes a note,
what should be done?
Can this executioner's blade
sever a golden chain?
Harsh laws for urgent times,
gentle handling for delicate matters.
Your Highness, it might be better
to first execute
the seven confirmed corrupt officials
to uphold the law,
and as for the other involved scholars,
(Sixian Hall)
send them to serve in the military.
This fulfills your goal
of purging the selection process,
while avoiding the risk
of alienating the noble families.
Great.
What a perfectly safe piece of advice.
Do you all know
how many innocent souls are buried
in the fraud cases of past dynasties?
The bribes in this year's examination
are piled to the ceiling.
Even the children
in the streets are singing,
"The rich claim the golden list,
while the poor bury their ink."
My father implemented
the talent selection system
to break
the noble families' monopoly
on officialdom,
giving students
from humble backgrounds a chance
to realize their ambitions
and showcase their talents.
Now, this buying and selling
of examination results
is crueler than the harsh officials
in the Discourses on Salt and Iron.
Poor scholars
pour their hearts out
and study hard for a decade,
only to end up as ghostwriters
for the rich.
I'll lay it on the line today.
Anyone involved
in this examination fraud,
from nobles down to petty clerks,
every single one of them
will not be spared.
Your Highness,
Commandery Princess Zhaoning's cousin,
Minister Tao's eldest grandson,
was also involved in the fraud.
The evidence is conclusive.
=Blossoms of Power=
(Adapted from the novel, After My
Bloom, All Flowers Wither by Jin Huang)
=Episode 20=
(East Palace)
Xihe, you came to see me
on your own accord.
I assume regarding your cousin,
your aunt has already pleaded with you.
You guessed correctly, Your Highness.
Xihe, I...
You don't need to say anything.
There's no need to show him favoritism.
Since my cousin made a mistake,
he should be dealt with accordingly.
People must always pay the price
for the mistakes they make.
Only then can they learn their lesson
and hold reverence for the law.
Then what about
your grandfather's family?
How do you consider them?
My grandfather is not at fault.
No one can use this
to falsely accuse him.
As for whether my aunt
will hold a grudge against me,
that is not my concern.
I have a clear conscience.
Why are you looking at me like that?
Along this journey,
you clearly need the support
of your maternal family the most,
yet you risk offending the Tao family
to place righteousness
above family loyalty.
I can see that
you're looking forward to
a peaceful and prosperous nation.
Qingzhi once sent me a policy essay.
Its insights were unique
and its arguments sweeping.
The essay began by stating,
"I have heard
that the essence of governance
lies in equitable land distribution
and the people's peace.
The teachings on regulating water
and land are still fresh in our minds.
Yet today, all fertile land
belongs to the wealthy,
while the poor have not even
a sliver of land to stand on."
You remember it word for word.
The writing was so bold,
and it's truly unforgettable.
Back then, my only thought
was to catch the person who poisoned me.
Over time,
my heart filled with resentment
and bitterness.
The master at the Taoist temple
suggested I travel.
Taking the imperial examination
at the time
was just a whim.
But I saw with my own eyes
candidates getting the exam questions
in advance
and swapping their papers on the spot,
while the examiners turned a blind eye.
I could have submitted a memorial
to the throne,
but I knew
even if I reported it then,
it would only clean up
the local practices temporarily.
It wouldn't serve
as a nationwide deterrent.
What I want
is a sweeping and decisive purge.
For at least ten years,
I want wrongdoers
not to even dare harbor evil thoughts,
and allow those with true ambition
to stand out.
Your time among the people back then
is what makes you so clear-headed
and thorough today.
But regarding this matter,
how did you know it was me?
I remember
the candidate they later investigated
was named Xiao Huaiqian.
Xiao and Xiao sound the same.
Hua was changed to Huai,
turning outward brilliance
into inner depth.
Yong was changed to Qian,
turning noble arrogance
into a humble demeanor.
It showed that the person
wanted to hide his prominent identity.
No matter how I disguise myself,
you can always see right through it.
Just like when we first met.
I also know that
while catching
the poisoner is important,
what you never forget
is eliminating the chronic poison
that has seeped into the nation's veins.
So regarding my cousin,
you need not worry.
Please enforce the law impartially
and set an example.
Now that we've discussed everything,
I should head back to the manor.
Before you go back,
I'd like to take you somewhere.
Come.
Here are your meatballs.
Enjoy your meal.
If others saw you right now,
who would think
you're the cold and heartless
Commandery Princess Zhaoning?
If you could see yourself right now,
you wouldn't think
you're the calculating
and deeply scheming Crown Prince.
Slow down.
You two,
come in and guess some riddles!
(A Lady Holding Up the Roof
Stabilizes the World)
Do you know the answer?
A roof radical over a lady
combined with the character for "lady"
makes the character "An" for peace.
(Peace)
It's a good riddle.
For the world to be at peace,
ladies should
naturally have their place.
This riddle is quite unique.
The bottom of "Qin"
is the character "He" for grain.
Grain is wood, and water nurtures wood.
Replacing it with water makes
the character "Tai" for prosperity.
Only with abundant agriculture
can the country prosper
and the people be at peace.
(National Prosperity and Peace)
Though I've long known
of your unmatched brilliance,
every single time,
you still manage to amaze me.
It's the riddle maker
who hid the foundation of the state
within the strokes of the characters.
It's the foundation of the state
hidden in your heart.
Would you care
to add a token of good fortune
to the blessing?
In the royal court,
I only wish for peace
and prosperity for the nation.
But when I am with you,
I only pray for our twin lotuses
to bloom.
It's beautiful.
The night is late and the dew is heavy.
Couldn't I take care of it for you?
Why must you trouble yourself?
If you catch a cold,
you'll have to drink
herbal medicine again.
This flower is delicate.
It will wither
if not carefully tended to.
I wouldn't feel at ease
leaving it to others.
Mo Yu,
go fetch some more hot spring water.
Yes.
The reason this Slender-Leaf Qionghua
is so precious
is that it can be used in medicine.
It nourishes the yin,
protects the lungs, and detoxifies.
The Crown Prince coughs frequently.
Half of it is a disguise
in front of others,
and half of it is real.
I'm afraid the residual poison hasn't
been cleared and has damaged his lungs.
So Her Highness works so hard
all for the Crown Prince.
Could this be
what the storybooks call
"the dawn of love
and deep-rooted affection"?
(Residence of the Heir
of the Marquis of Shunan)
Hurry up.
Handle with care.
Got it.
That Cui Jinbai.
I haven't seen him for days.
He's been busy with Crown Prince
on the fraud case.
I thought he had let me off the hook.
- Young Master.
Look at how carefully
he's picking things out.
Anyone who didn't know
would think he's planning
to live here for thirty years.
Halt.
What is it?
Where are you going?
Just going out for a stroll.
I'll go with you.
No need.
I suddenly feel
a bit tired.
I'll go back and rest.
Alright.
I have some business
at the Court of Judicial Review later.
Get some good rest.
Okay.
You go do your thing.
I won't bother you.
See you.
Young Master Bu,
you haven't been here for days.
It's not that I didn't want to come.
During the fraud case,
I had to keep a close eye
on the security of the capital.
Yu'er,
your little hands are getting
even softer and whiter.
Come.
Young Master Bu,
you're lingering among the beauties,
looking quite delighted.
Why are you here?
You're playing around
with official courtesans.
Do you know you've committed
the crime of corruption?
Stop talking nonsense.
Don't think because you're
in the Court of Judicial Review
and have been a Vice Minister
for a few years,
you can just pin crimes on people.
In our dynasty, official courtesans
are performing artists
belonging to the government.
According to the law,
officials who are overly intimate
with official courtesans
face ten years in prison.
I was just looking
at Yu'er's soft white hands
and joking around a bit.
It seems you know you're in the wrong.
I can let this matter go for now,
but you must promise me
never to set foot
in these pleasure houses again.
What gives you the right to deprive me
of my right to enjoy myself?
Are you that inseparable
from singing and dancing?
Yes. You don't know
how to appreciate it,
and you want to stop others
from appreciating it too.
You're simply unreasonable.
Fine.
I'll accompany you.
He's accompanying you?
Suit yourself.
Do you know what dance this is?
Isn't it just a water sleeve dance?
This is the Qingshang dance.
It originates
from the Han Dynasty Music Bureau.
Specifically, the three Qingshang modes
of Xianghe songs.
It features rare dances
and extraordinary talents.
Several emperors of the
previous dynasties loved this dance.
Later, it became widely popular
among the common people.
The Music Office continuously absorbed
and improved upon folk music and dance,
resulting in the spectacular performance
we see today.
You may step down.
Qian'er's pipa playing,
in the entire imperial capital,
can be considered unparalleled.
Then tell me, this piece,
White Snow in Spring Sunlight,
what makes it so unparalleled?
Spring Sunlight is derived
from all things sensing the spring,
and the gentle, soothing breeze.
White Snow
is derived from awe-inspiring purity,
and the crisp sound of snow on bamboo.
Her playing technique
is beautiful and fluent.
But it's too beautiful,
thus losing the original intention
of this piece.
Decadent music
is truly inferior.
Young Master Bu,
do you know...
- Young Master!
What's wrong, Young Master?
Are you feeling unwell?
My head hurts.
Go bring
Xie Yunhuai here.
You may have caught a cold.
I'll go get your medicine.
Have you forgotten?
Physician Xie
has gone beyond the frontier.
Forget it.
This is infuriating.
Young Master Bu,
where are you feeling unwell?
What are you doing here?
Don't you go to
the Court of Judicial Review?
Is this how the Young Master's Residence
treats its guests?
Won't you even offer me a seat?
Do you really not want
to see me that much?
What do you think?
Every single day,
you keep an eye on me
from morning till night.
One of these days,
you're going to drive me crazy.
If you could keep yourself in check,
I wouldn't have to.
Why should I?
I've lived freely in the imperial capital
since I was a child.
No one has ever tried
to keep me in line.
I've long been used to
living without restraints.
If you can't stand it, then move out.
It suits us both.
You're not leaving, are you?
Fine. I'll go.
Young Master.
Although Physician Xie isn't here,
a highly skilled foreign physician
has just arrived.
I'll go invite him over.
Get out.
Just get out.
Why are you sitting here?
Waiting for you to calm down.
Calm down?
The moment I see you, I can't calm down.
Then don't look at me.
Lord Cui,
I'm begging you.
Will you just leave me alone?
Fine.
I promise.
From now on, I'll try not to go
to those places so often.
Good.
But if you break your word,
I'll do what I did today again.
(East Palace)
Your Highness.
This time, I traveled
far beyond the borders
and brought back
an extraordinary person.
He is especially skilled
in detoxification.
I took the liberty
of having him diagnose you,
Your Highness.
Greetings, Your Highness.
Then I will trouble you, Physician Ale.
How could His Highness's blood
be like this?
Tell me,
how much time do I have left?
Originally, you had three to five years.
But Your Highness,
you've risked your life several times
and damaged your meridians.
Now,
you only have one year left.
Is it truly beyond saving?
There is one more method.
This set of golden needles
has been soaked in a poison-drawing
decoction Ale specially formulated.
They can be inserted into acupoints
to fight poison with poison.
However, this method,
compared to previous treatments,
will be a hundred times more painful.
A hundred times more painful?
The previous poison treatments
were as painful
as scraping bone and piercing the heart.
How can His Highness endure this?
Speak freely.
There are twelve needles in total.
Three needles break mortal bones.
Twelve needles shatter the soul.
By the eighth needle,
even the toughest man
will be in so much pain
that his soul will shatter.
You've experienced it yourself?
Let me see.
I am incompetent.
I could only endure four needles.
Why did you go to such lengths?
You secured a title of honor
for my mother.
Your kindness to me
is as deep as the sea.
Even if my body is smashed to pieces,
I am willing to do it.
We will use this method.
Whenever I think of her,
I know I cannot die.
As long as I can stay by her side,
even one more day is good.
Your Highness, why did you summon me
to the palace?
I've seen Yunhuai.
He told me some good news.
What good news?
Yunhuai said
right now,
I don't even have three
to five years left.
That's good news?
You won't have to keep your guard up
against me.
Isn't that good news?
How much time is left?
One year.
This might not be a bad thing.
After all, what you valued in me
from the start
was my short life.
Why don't we make a deal?
What deal?
My lifelong wish
is to marry you.
If you are willing to marry me,
I will form an alliance with you,
and help you keep the Shen family
and the Northwest Army safe.
Everything you want,
I will give to you.
You believe
that people's hearts are fickle.
Even if I were to have a change of heart
after we marry,
I wouldn't live long enough
to be your enemy.
If you become the Crown Princess,
it will make things much easier for you.
You can also help me fulfill
my unfulfilled wishes.
Your wish
is to find the one who poisoned you?
It used to be.
Now,
not entirely.
This poison
should not become a curse
that traps me.
No matter how much time
heaven grants me,
I should do more
meaningful things for the world.
These are the dates chosen
by the Ministry of Rites.
If you are willing
to join hands with me,
then pick one.
But don't pick one too far
in the future.
I'm afraid I won't live to see it.
As for your words today,
I will consider them carefully.
Xihe,
every word you say,
every single syllable,
I will keep firmly in my heart.
If you want to say something
that will break my heart,
don't say it lightly.
(Auspicious Day for Marriage: 10th Day
of the 2nd Month, 23rd Year of Youning)
(Auspicious Day for Marriage: 2nd Day
of the 3rd Month, 23rd Year of Youning)
(Auspicious Day for Marriage: 8th Day
of the 5th Month, 23rd Year of Youning)
♪A wall that collapses at a single push♪
♪Frost that melts at a single smile♪
♪How can you be this wonderful♪
♪I've hidden so many words♪
♪Too reluctant to tell you♪
♪So never uncover♪
♪The sand that slips away
with one grasp♪
♪The flower that withers
after one bloom♪
I was picking Immortal Vine,
and happened to save you.
Save me...
That was our first encounter.
There was absolutely
no scheming involved.
But as long as you believe
that I will never hurt you,
that is enough.
Do you know
why it withers once it leaves the water?
Because it was born
to be bathed in the gaze of lovers.
Do you know
how much I wanted you to ask,
"Where are you going?"
"What are you going to do?"
♪Give you a moon in return♪
Since I was nine,
I haven't known what joy is.
But now,
I know.
It is being with you.
I'm very easy to coax.
Even if it's a lie,
I'm willing to believe it.
I wonder if you would be willing
to marry me.
♪You'll never♪
♪Know how much I long to, long to♪
♪Wind that misses the grasp♪
♪Light that ignites at a single touch♪
♪A person can find strength
time and again♪
♪Our past♪
♪Has been full of ups and downs
along the way♪
♪Admitting my confusion
just like your regret♪
♪How hard can it be?♪
Your knot
looks more exquisite
the more I look at it.
I wonder when
I will also be on someone's mind,
and have someone
pray for my good fortune and longevity.
♪Stepping out of this long game
of hide-and-seek♪
♪The flustered mortal world♪
♪Your eyes remain clear and bright♪
(East Palace)
I thought
you wouldn't come.
Since you invited me,
I would naturally come.
So,
what is your answer?
For that one year,
I'll be a good wife to you.
Don't move.
You know very well
I'm only marrying you
because you have one year left to live.
Yet you're still so happy.
Each dawn, each dusk,
each moment together,
that will be a lifetime.
My life
rises and sets like the sun.
My heart
remains unchanged for eternity.
I chose the nearest auspicious date.
(Yong'an Hall)
Grandmother,
I came to see you as soon as I returned.
What a filial child.
How has your health been lately?
Good.
Greetings, Your Highness.
You may rise.
Greetings, Commandery Princess.
Greetings, Your Highness.
I asked Xihe to come keep me company.
She is about to marry the Crown Prince.
Soon,
she will become your sister-in-law.
I heard you will stay in the capital.
Yes.
Father has issued a decree,
appointing me
as the General of the Gallant Cavalry.
Congratulations, Your Highness.
I always remember
the times I spent with you.
Taking care of the children
in Gudu Garden together,
paying respects to the fallen soldiers
at the cemetery together.
Far away in Anlan,
in the dead of night,
I sometimes regretted
leaving the imperial capital.
You are a born soldier.
At that time, the imperial capital
wasn't the best place for you
to showcase your talents.
Your ideals and ambitions
belong on the battlefield.
Defending the country
is beyond reproach.
You made the right choice.
Don't worry.
I didn't come back this time
to pester you.
The past is in the past.
I only wish you
a smooth future
and to follow your heart.
I invited you here today
to pick out your wedding dress.
All the ceremonies for our wedding
are handled by the Palace Administration
and various departments,
in coordination
with the Ministry of Ceremonies.
But Xihe, you should
choose what you like.
Take your time.
I only hope that on the wedding day,
I can see joy in your eyes.
Thank you for your trouble,
Your Highness.
This booklet follows
the royal regulations
for your wedding attire.
Please take a look, Your Highness.
(Crown Prince's Wedding Attire Catalog)
If I may, Your Highness,
royal weddings in our dynasty
favor bright colors,
usually with crimson as the main color,
paired with various patterns.
This white pattern is so unique.
It looks like a sky full of stars.
All the wedding dresses
will be made according to Commandery
Princess Zhaoning's preferences.
Yes, Your Highness.
(Auspicious)
Your Highness,
the pearls on this veil
were personally selected for you
by the Crown Prince.
And he strung them one by one
with his own hands.
This shows
His Highness's sincerity
in marrying you.
Put it on.
Her Highness looks like
a fairy descending to earth.
Why are you crying on such a joyous day?
The bridal procession
from the East Palace is here!
Please have a seat, you two.
I'm not tired.
The Commandery Princess has arrived.
Bow.
Bow again.
Xihe,
your father and brother are not here.
Today, your uncle and I
will see you off to your marriage.
May the two of you
be of one mind and heart,
respect each other,
tie the knot forever,
and form a lifelong bond.
I wish you
mutual respect and harmony
in your marriage.
May you live in harmony,
continue the family line,
and grow old together.
Grandfather and Uncle, I will always
keep your earnest teachings in my heart.
Don't miss the auspicious hour.
Go.
The bride departs!
Set off.
Your Highness, please behave yourself.
On our wedding night,
with my beautiful bride,
perhaps you could teach me
how to behave.
Your Highness,
you and Xihe are newlyweds,
but you should still
exercise some restraint.
♪I've hidden so many words♪
♪Too reluctant to tell you♪
♪So never uncover♪
♪The sand that slips away
with one grasp♪
♪The flower that withers
after one bloom♪
♪Silently buried deep inside my heart♪
♪Every answer I gave♪
♪Was both bittersweet and absurd♪
♪Hiding my tear-filled eyes
when I hurt you♪
♪How hard it truly was?♪
♪The wounds that healed
with just a little comfort♪
♪The lies made whole
with a single embrace♪
♪Pretending to be brave
as if I'd never been hurt♪
♪It's a shame I never could♪
♪Give you a moon in return♪
♪With the same open heart you loved me♪
♪I've crossed the wasteland of memories♪
♪Never knowing I was lost♪
♪Why don't you take me away?♪
♪Lead me out of this endless game
of hide-and-seek♪
♪You'll never♪
♪Know how much I long to, long to♪
(No animals were harmed
in the making of this film)